LUKE BELLIVEAU

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

■ luke@belliveau.org

Q lukebelliveau

Luke is a full stack developer with over eight years of experience building valuable systems on a wide spectrum of scale. Though he has worked in a variety of contexts up and down the stack, he is happiest when focusing on front-end development or the building of developer-facing frameworks and services. For the last few years, he has worked as a consultant for various companies, working all along the stack with a focus on solving complex front-end

Skills

DEVELOPMENT & BUILD TOOLS

Babel

IntelliJ IDEA

npm

Eclipse

Xcode Gradle

FRAMEWORKS, SERVICES & RUNTIMES

React (+Native/VR)

React Router

Redux

Expo.io

TESTING Jest

testing-library

Cypress

Mocha

Enzyme

Jasmine

Sinon Selenium

testdouble

LANGUAGES

TypeScript JavaScript

Java Golang

Python

PIPELINE & DEPLOYMENT

Jenkins

Gitlab

Heroku

TFS

Employment

ZUUT.co

Lead Developer Dec. 2021 to Current

ZUUT is a computer-aided design tool that enables users to design and plan out their cannabis grow operations in a 2D collaborative space, then purchase the equipment they need. It is a web application that runs in the browser and aims to replicate a "Google Docs" -esque feel of sharing and collaboration. Luke was the sole developer on this project, taking the application from inception to launch alongside the founder, and implemented features such as:

- A fast and interactive 2D computer-aided design interface where users can drag, arrange and modify items to design a grow plan, running in the browser canvas and written with Next.is/React and Redux
- Implemented an item interaction & collision detection engine to control the behavior and appearance of items on the design tool, complete with a comprehensive test suite
- Implemented an item management frontend with Airtable, enabling nontechnical employees to modify the items available in the grow planner via a simple spreadsheet interface Account management enabling users to save, modify, share, and collaborate on as many plans as they want, backed by Firebase Authentication and Realtime Database.
- Enabled content partners to contribute blog posts using the Contentful CMS
- Leveraged static/server-side rendering and bundle optimization techniques to achieve fast, cache-busting deployments and high performance (+ Lighthouse scores) anywhere in

NuWave Technologies

Tech Lead

At NuWave Technologies, Luke is in charge of designing, developing and delivering the NuWave suite of web applications. In his time at NuWave, he led the Prizm Console product development from inception to launch, and is currently working on bringing their other web applications into the modern age of web development.

- Assisting with product design, turning rough sketches & ideas into well-defined technical tasks, and delegating work among team
- Defining code standards that are useful, reasonable, and not overly intrusive, using tools including Prettier, ESLint, and TypeScript
 Mentoring junior developers, designing training programs and holding "office hours" to bring team members up to speed on technical topics
- Building a production ready front-end with TypeScript & React, tested with Jest and Cypress
 Building a CI pipeline to test, build, and deploy code using tools including Jenkins, Docker, and AWS (primarily EC2 & S3)
- Successfully architecting & executing a move from AngularJS to React codebase in two of NuWave's legacy applications enabling rapid development to continue after the sunsetting of AngularJS, and the introduction of test pipelines with Jest and Cypress

Grubhub

Senior Cloud Infrastructure Engineer

lune 2016 to Oct. 2018

At GrubHub, Luke serves as a Cloud Infrastructure engineer. That means he designs and develops frameworks, tools, and services that enable other GrubHub engineers to do their jobs as efficiently as they can.

Beyond his work on building frameworks & tools using Java, JavaScript and Python, Luke has had loads of experience with AWS, Docker, and Spinnaker. His accomplishments at GrubHub include:

- Engineering changes to core framework to facilitate communication between microservices in a new Envoy service mesh architecture
- Leading integration of SMS service with a new provider, handling the development, evaluation, and communication with stakeholders on both ends
 Ownership of Notifications stack of microservices in Java (with Guice and Spring), spanning SMS, mobile push, email, and fax functionalities
- Independently building a service in React & Python used by Site Reliability Engineers to view system status and make changes during outages · Designing a new microservice architecture and Cassandra data model used for a new notifications template authoring service

ThoughtWorks

Senior Software Engineer

Cybersecurity Startup

June 2018-Current

New York, NY

• Built interface enabling security analysts to examine potential cybersecurity threats and take action

- · Collaborated with potential users, experience designers, and product owners to create direction and design for new product
- Worked with experience designers to create and implement a set of custom data visualizations using SVGs and Highcharts atop a Vue front end
- · Built a comprehensive BFF in Golang to aggregate, analyze, & perform operations on data before serving to the client

E-Commerce Retailer

July 2017-June 2018 Boca Raton, FL

- Designed APIs to facilitate communication among new, modular services and legacy REST endpoints in Node.js and C#
- Architected modules to pass messages between GCP Pub/Sub, Kafka & SOL databases in Node.is, C# and Java
- Introduced and championed best testing practices in a Node.js codebase using Jest, testdouble.js, and Mocha
- Served as line of communication between stakeholders for multiple companies, managing a variety of codebases, priorities, and business requirements Coached client developers on XP practices such as test-driven development and pair programming
- Established and facilitated agile practices on a young team including retros, code reviews, and tech debt management

Insurance Provider

November 2016 - June 2017

Lansing, MI

- · Served as an application developer and JavaScript specialist on a web platform for one of the largest insurance companies in the U.S.
- Led design of React component hierarchies and Redux state management architecture for two greenfield codebases
- Designed comprehensive unit, integration & functional test suites, drove account-wide direction of testing strategy with Enzyme, Chai and Mocha
 Coached developers & QAs in React, Redux, ES6 fundamentals & best practices Wrote & tested code for a Spring Boot microservice architecture

Consulting Firm August 2016 - November 2016

- · Developed software used to track employee information for a leading consulting firm
- Extended codebase for a web application built with Java & ESS JavaScript, SpringMVC, and PostgreSQL, tested with Jasmine, Selenium, and JUnit
- Practiced continuous integration on a snapCl pipeline, deploying to Heroku
- Spearheaded successful effort to integrate Spring Security and Okta SSO into the application
- Practiced non-technical skills by facilitating discussions on team ceremonies, providing a developer perspective on story analysis, and leading communication between the team and external entities such as product owners, DevOps, and domain experts.

Selected Side Projects

Luke independently built a platform enabling charitable donors and benefactors to match donations to charitable organizations. Luke built this platform with a React front-end leveraging APIs from Twitter, Zapier, and Dropbox. After open sourcing the project, Luke managed an ad-hoc team of 20 developers, analysts, and experience designers located in six different countries around the world. At its peak, matchUS was servicing over 1,600 users in a day. Through matchUS, users shared over \$760,000 in matched donations.

Luke was commissioned to build the official Android app for world-famous music collective BROCKHAMPTON. SATURATION is used by the band to debut new music videos to fans before they are officially released on other channels, such as YouTube. Luke obtained assets from the band's graphic designers and built the app over a weekend, publishing it in the same week. The application was built with React Native on the Expo platform. SATURATION has been installed by over 10,000 users and enjoys a rating of five stars on the Google Play

Education

University of Connecticut

B.S. Computer Science 2016

Luke attained a major GPA of 3.67. Among other practical achievements such as building a Bash clone and C-- compiler from scratch, Luke led an IBM-sponsored development team for his capstone project making an IFTTT clone in Node.